<LTIDocs><div><h3><h1 class=" toc-headings">5         Representing Basic Launch Links in a Cartridge<toc class="toc-5"></toc></h1></h3><p>Since there are no changes to these formats in LTI v1.1, we are not advancing the version of the name spaces in this section.</p><p>A Basic LTI link is a simplified and self-contained LTI link. A basic launch link is defined in the resource section of an IMS Common Cartridge as follows:</p><p></p><p>       &lt;resource identifier="I_00010_R" type="imsbasiclti_xmlv1p0"></p><p>              &lt;file href="I_00001_R/BasicLTI.xml"/></p><p>       &lt;/resource></p><p>The <strong>href</strong> in the resource entry refers to a file path in the cartridge that contains an XML description of the basic launch link.</p><p></p><p>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?></p><p>&lt;cartridge_basiclti_link xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticc_v1p0"</p><p>    xmlns:blti = "http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsbasiclti_v1p0"</p><p>    xmlns:lticm ="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticm_v1p0"</p><p>    xmlns:lticp ="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticp_v1p0"</p><p>    xmlns:xsi = "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"</p><p>    xsi:schemaLocation = "http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticc_v1p0 http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/lti/ltiv1p0/imslticc_v1p0.xsd</p><p>http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsbasiclti_v1p0 http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/lti/ltiv1p0/imsbasiclti_v1p0.xsd</p><p>http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticm_v1p0 http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/lti/ltiv1p0/imslticm_v1p0.xsd</p><p>http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslticp_v1p0 http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/lti/ltiv1p0/imslticp_v1p0.xsd"></p><p>    &lt;blti:title>Grade Book&lt;/blti:title></p><p>    &lt;blti:description>Grade Book with many column types&lt;/blti:description></p><p>    &lt;blti:custom></p><p>        &lt;lticm:property name="keyname">value&lt;/lticm:property></p><p>    &lt;/blti:custom></p><p>    &lt;blti:extensions platform="my.lms.com"></p><p>        &lt;lticm:property name="keyname">value&lt;/lticm:property></p><p>    &lt;/blti:extensions></p><p>    &lt;blti:launch_url>url to the basiclti launch URL&lt;/blti:launch_url></p><p>    &lt;blti:secure_launch_url>secure url to the basiclti launch URL&lt;/blti:secure_launch_url></p><p>    &lt;blti:icon>url to an icon for this tool (optional)&lt;/blti:icon></p><p>    &lt;blti:secure_icon>secure url to an icon for this tool (optional)>&lt;/blti:secure_icon></p><p>    &lt;blti:vendor></p><p>&lt;lticp:code>vendor.com&lt;/lticp:code></p><p>&lt;lticp:name>vendor.name&lt;/lticp:name></p><p>        &lt;lticp:description>This is a vendor of learning tools.&lt;/lticp:description></p><p>&lt;lticp:url>http://www.vendor.com/&lt;/lticp:url></p><p>        &lt;lticp:contact></p><p>&lt;lticp:email>support@vendor.com&lt;/lticp:email></p><p>        &lt;/lticp:contact></p><p>    &lt;/blti:vendor></p><p>    &lt;cartridge_bundle identifierref="BLTI001_Bundle"/></p><p>    &lt;cartridge_icon identifierref="BLTI001_Icon"/></p><p>&lt;/cartridge_basiclti_link></p><p></p><p>The <strong>launch_url</strong> contains the URL to which the LTI Launch is to be sent.   The <strong>secure_launch_url</strong> is the URL to use if secure http is required.  One of either the <strong>launch_url</strong> or the <strong>secure_launch_url</strong> must be specified. It is acceptable to specify both and if both are specified, the TC decides which to use. Typically, the TC will use a <strong>secure_launch_url</strong> when embedding the Tool in a secure page and the <strong>launch_url</strong> when embedding the tool in a non-secure page. So, it&amp;rsquo;s important that the TP provides the same functionality whether the <strong>launch_url</strong> or <strong>secure_launch_url </strong>is used.</p><p></p><p>The <strong>icon</strong> and <strong>secure_icon</strong> are both optional and indicate a URL to be used for an icon to the tool.</p><p>Once the basic launch link is defined in the resources section of the cartridge manifest, it can be referenced in the organization section of the manifest as needed:</p><p></p><p style="margin-left:29.25pt;">&lt;item identifier="BasicLTI1" identifierref="I_00010_R"><br></br>
		        &lt;title>Homework Problems&lt;/title></p><p>&lt;/item></p><p></p><p>The TC will generally display the <strong>title</strong> in the <strong>item</strong> entry in the user interface rather than <strong>title</strong> in the <strong>basic_lti_link</strong> entry.</p><p>The optional <strong>custom</strong> section can contain a set of key value pairs that were placed in the link in the system that originally authored the link.  For example if the link were a section in an eTextbook, there might be a setting like:<br></br></p><p style="margin-left:.5in;">&lt;parameter key="section">1.2.7&lt;/parameter></p><p>These parameters are sent back to the external tool when the tool is launched.  If a basic launch link is imported and then exported the <strong>custom</strong> should be maintained across the import/export process unless the intent is to re-author the link.</p><p>The <strong>extensions</strong> section allows the hosting TC to add its own key/value pairs to the link. The TC may use extensions to store information that the TC or authoring environment might use across an export-import cycle. In order to allow multiple sets of extensions to be contained in the same basic launch descriptor, authoring environments should add the <strong>platform</strong> attribute and include an identifier that identifies the authoring environment.</p><p>It is possible to include the icon for the link in the cartridge instead of including it as a URL using the <strong>cartridge_icon</strong> entry in the descriptor.  The <strong>identifierref</strong> attribute points to a link that includes the icon image and a dependency is added to the resource section of the basic launch resource entry in the manifest as shown below.</p><p></p><p>       &lt;resource identifier="I_00010_R" type="imsbasiclti_xmlv1p0"></p><p>              &lt;file href="I_00001_R/BasicLTI.xml"/></p><p style="margin-left:.5in;">&lt;dependency identifierref="BLTI001_Icon"/></p><p>       &lt;/resource></p><p></p><p>&lt;resource identifier="BLTI001_Icon"</p><p>type="associatedcontent/imscc_xmlv1p0/learning-application-resource"></p><p>              &lt;file href="BLTI001_Media/learning_icon.gif"/><br></br>
		       &lt;/resource></p><p></p><div class="toc-item-anchor"><a name="toc-6"></a></div></div></LTIDocs>