<LTIDocs><div><h3><h1 class=" toc-headings">6         Using Learning Information Services with LTI<toc class="toc-6"></toc></h1></h3><p>A TP may be given access to a subset of IMS Learning Information Services (LIS) [LIS, 11] by a TC including additional parameters in launch requests.  The LIS services do not need to be provided by the TC, a third system such as a Student Information System may be the endpoint supplied for these services.</p><p align="center"><img border="0" height="192" src="/sites/default/files/lti/ltiv1p2/images/ltiIMGv1p2pd-image003.gif" width="473"></img></p><p align="center"><strong>Figure 6.1</strong> The TP taking advantage of LIS services.</p><p>Support by a TC of LIS-related services is optional.  The Outcomes service introduced in LTI 1.1 is described in a separate document [LTI, 14 OM].</p><p>In order to interact with LIS services provided to the TP or another system by mechanisms outside the scope of this document, the TC may include the following additional launch parameters if the data is available to the TC for the particular launch:</p><p><strong>lis_person_sourcedid=school.edu:user</strong><em>(Recommended)</em><br></br>
		This parameter contains the LIS identifier for the user account that is performing this launch.    The example syntax of "school:user" is not the required format &amp;ndash; <strong>lis_person_sourcedid</strong> is simply a unique identifier (i.e., a normalized string). This field is recommended and its content and meaning are defined by LIS [LIS, 11].</p><p><strong>lis_course_offering_sourcedid=school.edu:SI182-F08</strong><em>(Recommended)</em><br></br><strong>lis_course_section_sourcedid=school.edu:SI182-001-F08</strong><em>(Recommended)</em><br></br>
		These parameters contain LIS course identifiers associated with the context of this launch.  These fields are recommended and their content and meaning are defined by LIS [LIS, 11].</p><p></p><div class="toc-item-anchor"><a name="toc-7"></a></div></div></LTIDocs>